<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Folkhouse</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2020-03-29T18:22:49-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Griffin Moore</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Visit to Earthship Biotecture</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/29/earthship-biotecture/"/>
   <updated>2020-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/29/earthship-biotecture</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/earthship.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Earthship Biotecture in Taos, New Mexico&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently visited &lt;a href=&quot;google.com&quot;&gt;Earthship Biotecture&lt;/a&gt; in Taos, New Mexico&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introduction</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/28/introduction/"/>
   <updated>2020-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/28/introduction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My name is Griffin. I currently live in Brooklyn, New York and work remotely as a user-interface designer for a company in California. I’ve created this blog to log different things I am reading and thinking about as I consider a next stage in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular I hope to share findings in the subjects of designing shelter, decentralism and degrowth, and the pursuit of self-sufficiency. Living off-grid has been a personal interest of mine since my early 20s (now 31 years old). I’ve done a fair bit of reading on the subject, but living in New York City has prevented me from accruing any actual experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this during the COVID-19 pandemic which has essentially put the planet on lockdown. This development has reinforced for me the critical importance of self-reliance– a concept we in the United States and in similar nations have moved dangerously far from. Perhaps not entirely by our own design, but through the coercive force of industrialization.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
