<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Folkhouse</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2020-03-30T21:23:56-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Griffin Moore</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Visit to Earthship Biotecture</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/30/earthship-biotecture/"/>
   <updated>2020-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/30/earthship-biotecture</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/earthship.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Earthship Biotecture in Taos, New Mexico&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Earthship is a type of house built with natural and recycled materials with energy conservation in mind. It is designed to produce water, electricity, and food for its own use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner, María Elena, and I visited &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.earthshipglobal.com&quot;&gt;Earthship Biotecture&lt;/a&gt; in Taos, New Mexico about two weeks ago. Unfortunately we had just a day and a half there before COVID-19 urged our early return to New York, but it was still a great experience. We stayed in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/22567280&quot;&gt;small recently-built studio-layout Earthship&lt;/a&gt; that can be rented out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drive from our previous stay in Santa Fe was quite barren so when we finally arrived alongside the Earthship community it actually felt surreal. We had seen the buildings online and on film, but seeing them firsthand felt markedly different. I’m not one for New Age aesthetics or the bohemian, crystal type stuff which Earthships can sometimes espouse, but in this strange desert context it seemed more acceptable. Still, I appreciated our rental being styled more traditionally!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Earthship has one wall of windows and three walls of earth-packed tires enclosed in adobe or a similar material. The floor and walls act as thermal mass, storing solar heat entering throughout the day to be naturally released when the home’s air temperature falls. Water is captured from the roof and used three times before returning to the landscape: first by showers and sinks, then indoor plants, then to toilets for flushing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earthships seem to be quite well known these days. I’m not sure when I first learned about them, but I bought Michael Reynolds’ three volume book set on eBay just last year after María Elena began research for a tangentially related project and developed her own interest. The books are actually &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.earthshipglobal.com/books&quot;&gt;on sale&lt;/a&gt; now for just $15 a piece– cheaper than I found them on eBay. And earlier this year we watched &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.garbagewarrior.com&quot;&gt;Garbage Warrior&lt;/a&gt; which documents Michael Reynolds’ quest to establish a legal test site for experimental shelter.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introduction</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/29/introduction/"/>
   <updated>2020-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/29/introduction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My name is Griffin Moore. I currently live in Brooklyn, New York and work remotely as a user-interface designer for a software company. I’ve created this blog to log different things I am reading and thinking about as I consider the next stage in my life. I don’t expect any mass-appeal, but simply feel an urge to compile some of ideas I have come across over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular I hope to post findings on the subjects of designing shelter, decentralism and degrowth, and the pursuit of self-sufficiency. Living off-grid has been a personal interest of mine since my early 20s (now 31 years old). I’ve done a fair bit of reading on the subject, but living in New York City has prevented me from accruing any actual experience. So I am just a student and that is the tone I wish to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this during the COVID-19 pandemic which has essentially put the planet on lockdown. This development has reinforced for me the critical importance of self-reliance– a concept we in the United States and in similar nations have moved dangerously far from. Perhaps not entirely by our own design, but spurred on by the coercive force of industrialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, industrialization and standardization have afforded us several luxuries. It’s one thing to design an off-grid existence within an industrial society– benefitting from the incredible access to goods and services– but can the system be redesigned in a way to meet a good standard of comfort while respecting all people and planet? Undoubtedly it will require significant cultural change. How we source energy, how we eat, how we build, how we travel– practically every aspect of our lives is, in this moment, performed without adequate consideration of the whole. I suppose this is the lofty question I wish to consider here. How can we better design our society for the benefit of everyone?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
